Guide to the Greek Committee Letters, 1879-1897 MS 133
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Greek Committee Letters
1879-1897
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Unknown
MS 133
0.25 Linear Feet (1 folder of 41 letters)
The correspondence includes letters and post cards from noted liberals of the period in Great Britain. Most are written to the Secretary of the Committee, Lewis Sergeant.
Biographical Note
The "Greek Committee" was formed at the outbreak of the Greco-Turkish war of 1878-1897. Originating in Great Britain, the committee's purpose was to promote support among Britons for Greece against the "despotic power" of Turkey.
Scope and Contents
The correspondence includes letters and post cards from noted liberals of the period in Great Britain. Most are written to the Secretary of the Committee, Lewis Sergeant. Sergeant was on the editorial staff of The Daily Chronicle and was particularly interested in the politics and literature of modern Greece. Correspondents include Lord Rosebery, Herbert Chamberlain, Sir C.W. Dilke, Sir J. Bryce, Leveson Gower (regarding the Memorial from the Thessalians of Athens), Bishop of Manchester, Max Muller, Sir William Watson, L.H. Courtney, J.P. Mahaffy, Roden Noel, Ernest Myers, Karl Blind (regarding Russia's renewed push toward Constantinople), and G.A. Sala.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored on-site at the Woodson Research Center.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from Myers (dealer) from funds donated by Friends of Fondren
Index Terms
Subjects
Authors
Document Types
letters (correspondence)
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Unknown to Lewis Sergeant, October 8, 1878 (Letter 1)
  - Unknown to Lewis Sergeant, June 2, 1879 (Letter 2)
  - Karl Blind to Lewis Sergeant, June 6, 1879 (Letter 3)
  - Unknown to Lewis Sergeant, June 8, 1879 (Letter 4)
  - Roden Noel to Lewis Sergeant, June 21, 1879 (Letter 5)
  - Unknown to Lewis Sergeant, July 3, 1879 (Letter 6)
  - Unknown to unknown, July 9, 1879 (Letter 7)
  - J. Bryce to Lewis Sergeant, August 4, 1879 (Letter 8)
  - Unknown to Lewis Sergeant, August 20, 1879 (Letter 9)
  - Ernest Myers to Lewis Sergeant, September 13, 1879 (Letter 10)
  - J. Bryce to Lewis Sergeant, January 12, 1880 (Letter 11)
  - Charles W. Dilke to Lewis Sergeant, January 29, 1880 (Letter 12)
  - J. Chamberlain to Lewis Sergeant, February 19, 1880 (Letter 13)
  - Unknown to Lewis Sergeant, February ??, 1880 (Letter 14)
  - Unknown to Lewis Sergeant, October 29, 1880 (Letter 15)
  - Unknown to Lewis Sergeant, November 4, 1880 (Letter 16)
  - G.A. Sala to Lewis Sergeant, November 22, 1880 (Letter 17)
  - The Duke of Westminster to Lewis Sergeant, November 23, 1880 (Letter 18)
  - The Bishop of Manchester to Lewis Sergeant, November 26, 1880 (Letter 19)
  - Max Muller to Arthur Arnold, November 30, 1880 (Letter 20)
  - Herbert F. Gladstone to Lewis Sergeant, November 30, 1880 (Letter 21)
  - Unknown to Lewis Sergeant, January 10, 1881 (Letter 22)
  - Unknown to Lewis Sergeant, January 11, 1881 (Letter 23)
  - Leveson Gower to Lewis Sergeant, March 19, 1881 (Letter 24)
  - Unknown to Lewis Sergeant, April 12, 1881 (Letter 25)
  - G.A. Sala to Lewis Sergeant, January 23, 1882 (Letter 26)
  - G.A. Sala to Lewis Sergeant, March 1, 1882 (Letter 27)
  - Unknown to unknown, December 15, 1882 (Letter 28)
  - Unknown to Lewis Sergeant, January 26, 1893 (Letter 29)
  - Unknown to Lewis Sergeant, February 24, 1893 (Letter 30)
  - C.W. Dilke to Lewis Sergeant, March 3, 1897 (Letter 31)
  - L.H. Courtney to unknown, March 5, 1897 (Letter 32)
  - Unknown to Lewis Sergeant, March 7, 1897 (Letter 33)
  - William Watson to Lewis Sergeant, March 7, 1897 (Letter 34)
  - C.W. Dilke to Lewis Sergeant, March 8, 1897 (Letter 35)
  - Unknown to Lewis Sergeant, May 7, 1897 (Letter 36)
  - J. Bryce to unknown, November 17, (no year given) (Letter 37)
  - J.P. Mahaffy to unknown, December 22, (no year given) (Letter 38)
  - Unknown to Lewis Sergeant, February 2 (no year given) (Letter 39)
  - Unknown to Lewis Sergeant, no date (Letter 40)
  - C.W. Dilke to Lewis Sergeant, no date. (Letter 41)